JAMES ROSKELL

Poulton-le-Fylde - FY6 7EJ Email: <u>JamesRoskell1@yahoo.com</u>

PERSONAL PROFILE

A motivated and organised individual with a passion for game and software development. Having gained a degree in Software Engineering Game Development, I have experience with C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and C++. Knowledgeable in project work with particular focus in game development and programming, having created a gaming platform using Unity and Unreal, and a QR code as a marketing tool during the course work placement. Excellent abilities working as part of a team as well as individually with skills in Microsoft, and Programming, with experience of VS Studio Code. I have a vision to create accessible websites for internet users.

CORE SKILLS

- Microsoft Packages
- ◆ Teamwork
- ♦ Reliable
- ◆ Time & Workload Management
- ♦ Organisation
- ♦ Technological Passion
- Programming
- ♦ Game creation

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ◆ Unity Game Engine
- ♦ C++
- ◆ C#
- ♦ JavaScript
- ♦ HTML
- ♦ CSS
- ♦ MySQL
- ♦ Monogame

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Online Retail Inputter

Jan 2017 - Present - Oxfam, Poulton Le Fylde

Responsible for researching the valuations of items for sale within an ecommerce capacity. I input and upload high value donated items onto the charity's online website ensuring the correct pricing for products. I maximise income by utilising Oxfams online presence to inform customers with descriptive titles and product information to sell goods, as well I ensure detailed photographs of each item. I maintained inventory of each item posted and sold, recording these appropriately and following procedures.

Office Assistant

Sept 2016 – Jan 2017 - British Heart Foundation, Blackpool.

Responsible for ensuring all customer receipts were filed away alphabetically following the organisations data protection policy and GDPR procedure. I also supported staff in administrative tasks including archiving receipts and documents held for a 3year period.

QUALIFICATIONS

University Centre; Blackpool and Fylde College: Sept 2019 – May 2021. Software Engineering Game Design (BSc Hons) 2:2 Degree

- Advanced Games Programming
- ♦ Human Computer Interaction
- Online Multiplayer Gaming
- Entrepreneurial Management and Project Control

◆ Dissertation - Unity development: the impact of sound on player progression within a range of game genres

University Centre; Blackpool and Fylde College Sept 2019 – May 2020. Software Engineering Game Design Foundation Degree

- Software Technical Design Documentation
- ♦ 3D Game Programming
- ♦ Game Engine Modifications
 - Unity game mechanic Double jump
 - o Unreal game mechanic Double jump
- ♦ 3D Rigging & Animation
 - o Experience in 3D modelling software such as 3DS Max.

Projects:

- Work Based Learning
 - Programmed and created a platform game called 'Avoid the Deadlines' using Unity, which is a fun and easy game to navigate to attract students on to the course.
 - Developed a marketing tool for a local church, a QR code to print on their booklets & notice board for parishioners to scan with their mobile devices to navigate to their social media page.
- Group Project
 - Created a platform-based game with Unity called 'Finna', I integrated Audio and a User Interface of the health bar as well as supporting with design for each level.

Blackpool and The Fylde College – Sept 2017 – June 2018 Level 3 Computing – Distinction

- Information Technology Systems
- ♦ Client-Side Customisation Web Pages
- Digital Graphics
- ♦ Software Design & Development
- ♦ Computer Networks

GCSE English - C

GSCE - Maths - D

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Digital Skills Award – May 2021; Blackpool & Fylde College.

HOBBIES & INTEREST

I am an avid Ebay seller with an interest in ecommerce, I enjoy the process of selling items, developing my photography skills and gaining an understanding of online marketing. I enjoy keeping updated on technological and IT information and have an interest in web design. I am a keen gamer, who enjoys adventure type games.

REFERENCES

Sara Marie Bramwell, Oxfam, Poulton Le Flyde. 01253 894548. oxfamshopf1036@oxfam.org.uk

Lee Holroyd, University Centre; Blackpool & The Fylde College. 01253 352352. lhol@blackpool.ac.uk